# LUZ ANGELIQUE MADRAZO

## FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



956-467-6118



luzm321@yahoo.com



https://luzm321.github.io



https://github.com/luzm321

# **PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW**

I have had 3 fruitful years of experience as a pediatric registered nurse in the healthcare field prior to establishing my journey in software development. My newfound zeal for coding honed my critical thinking aptitude to solve complex problems by implementing logic while collaborating in a team setting. The tech industry enables me to implement the skills that I have developed with my passion for life-long learning, creativity, and helping others. I feel fulfilled knowing I can make a positive impact by creating software applications that can help improve our quality of life as I continue to grow and learn new technologies.

## TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL (NSS)
Full-Stack Software Developer | May 2021 - Nov 2021

Six months (full-time) of rigorous software development training program with engaging, lab-based, and collaborative learning in JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSON server, and ReactJS, C#/.NET, MVC, and SQL Server.

- Implemented fundamentals of object-oriented programming through group and individual projects
- Applied principles of entity relationship diagrams (ERDs) to visualize data structures and wireframing for planning projects in an Agile environment
- Collaborated on several projects in a team and remote setting to build web applications from scratch utilizing the aforementioned tech stack with CSS/Bulma framework for design, external APIs, JSON local server database with flat data structure, and SQL Server to attain CRUD functionality

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## FRONT-END

- HTML5
- CSS3/Bulma/Material UI/Bootstrap CSS Frameworks
- JavaScript
- JSON Server Database
- ReactJS/JSX
- Git/Github

## **BACK-END**

- C#/.NET
- MVC
- SQL Server

## MIDDLEWARE TESTING

- Manual Testing with test case scenarios
- Postman and Swagger API Testing tools
- MOVEit Automation SFTP
- IBM MQ and RfhUtil to test MQ and IIB applications
- MUnit Test framework for MuleSoft integration/API platform

## **PROJECTS**

#### Panda-Aia! | Front-End Capstone | ReactJS

Panda-Aja! is a flashcard-based, Korean language learning application that features an innovative approach to learning Korean with meaningful and user-friendly interface.

- Integrates various forms of user interaction by implementing translation, speech, and text features for speech synthesis and recognition functionalities.
- Designed as a CRUD app and is supported by a flat data-structure utilizing JSON Server local database along with being styled with Bulma framework and CSS3.
- Built with ReactJS and supported by Web Speech API, Microsoft Translator Text external API, SweetAlert2 npm. react-animations, and node fetch proxy server.



https://github.com/luzm321/panda-aja

## Marvel Alliance | Back-End Capstone | Full-Stack React + Web API (C#/.NET)

Marvel Alliance is a turn-based strategy card game that utilizes Marvel characters with generated power stats to simulate an engaging, fun, and interactive card game experience.

- Users can perform CRUD operations on a deck and card along with playing a game against a simple AI (NPC) that attacks the opponent when it's their turn. Each defending character card's health points are decremented based on the attacking character's calculated power points. The player that has no cards left in their hand loses the game.
- Designed as a Full-Stack app that implements the Marvel Comics API and SuperHero Search API along with being styled with Bulma/Material UI framework and CSS3.
- Built with ASP.NET Core Web API, SQL Server, ReactJS, and Firebase Auth, along with SweetAlert2 npm, and react-animations npm.



https://github.com/luzm321/marvel-alliance

# PROJECTS CONTINUED

#### Social Buzz | React Nutshell | Group Project

Social Buzz is a web application built with the ReactJS library with CRUD functionality and utilization of ISON server database that enables users to organize daily tasks, events, news articles, friends, and interact with other users/friends via chat messages in a public message board.

- Social media platform built with three other teammates and completed over the course of a one week sprint
- Specifically built the messages page with all its functionalities along with the CSS styling for the page



https://github.com/NSS-Day-Cohort-49/reactnutshell-state-slingers

## **WORK FXPFRIFNCF**

Associate SDET | HCA Healthcare (HealthTrust PG) | December 2021 - June 2022

- Ensured quality of product and detected bugs/defects of project deliverables prior to reaching the end user via happy path, functional, and negative manual testing of use cases.
- Designed and implemented test scenarios to validate reliability and code coverage of integrations/interfaces developed for clients.
- Investigate issues encountered from failed tests or bugs and communicate them with the data integration engineers within the team.
- Contribute ideas and perspective to solve problems.

Triage Pediatric Neurosurgery RN | MONROE CARELL JR VANDERBILT CHILDREN'S HOSPITAL | November 2019 - February 2021

- Utilize critical thinking skills and knowledge to triage patient calls/clinical concerns for providers to address
- Provide instructions to families for managing post-operative care and urgent complications of neurosurgery to monitor
- Worked with eStar (Epic Electronic Health Record System) for documentation of nursing care and triage

## **WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED**

Pediatric Medical-Surgical RN | Rio Grande Regional Hospital | July 2018 - July 2019

- Provide holistic nursing care to children and families in collaboration with other members of the interdisciplinary health team
- Assess, plan, implement, and evaluate all assigned patient care based on the developmental, physical, and psycho-social needs of each patient
- Work with Meditech EHR (electronic health record) system that provides clinical charting for health care professionals

Certified Nursing Assistant | McAllen Medical Center | January 2015 - August 2015

 Under supervision of nurses: take vital signs, assist clients with activities of daily living, and provide optimal client care

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Nashville Software School**

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp | May 17, 2021 - November 05, 2021

#### The University of Texas Rio Grande Valley

Bachelor of Science in Nursing | Summa Cum Laude | August 2016 - May 2018

#### The University of Texas Pan-American

Bachelor of Science in Biology (Minor in Psychology) | Summa Cum Laude | August 2011 - December 2014